JOHN KIM

FREMONT, CA 94538

(510) 513-7376 | john@hillodesign.com | www.hillodesign.com

PROFILE:

5+ years of UX, UI, Web, and Graphic design experience as a Remote Contractor and In-House Experience, In Teams, Startups, Businesses And Corporations. Designed User Interface and User Experience Designs for Clients across the United States and Canada. San Francisco Bay Area/Silicon Valley Local and US Citizen.

SKILLSETS & TOOLS:

Adobe Creative Suite, Adobe XD, Figma, InVision, Wireframing, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Balsamiq, Webflow, Miro, xMind, Userflow, Mind Mapping, Journey Mapping, Storyboarding, Scenarios, Personas, Card Sort, User Interview, Usabilityhub, Surveys, Google Suite

EDUCATION:

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (BS), GRAPHIC INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - USER EXPERIENCE

Arizona State University (ASU) | Sep 2021 to Present | Phoenix, AZ (Current)

BACHELOR OF FINE ART (BFA), INTERACTION DESIGN

California College of the Arts (CCA) | Jun 2019 to Dec 2020 | San Francisco, CA and Oakland, CA (Transfer)

EXPERIENCE:

Freelance UI/UX Designer — Hillodesign

San Francisco Bay Area, CA | January 2016 - Present

- Designed User Interface and User Experience Designs for Clients across the United States and Canada. Maintained Websites and Web Servers, with HTML/CSS/JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, React.JS.
- 5+ years of UI/UX design experience as a Remote Freelancer and In-House Experience, In Teams, Startups, Businesses And Corporations.
- 5+ years of UI/UX design experience as a Remote Freelancer and In-House Experience, In Teams, Startups, Businesses And Corporations.

UI/UX Designer — Legacy Pictures

Los Angeles, CA | July 2021 - Present

- Redesigned Web Application with Adobe XD. Created deliverables with multiple iterations of User Interface Elements and variants of home screen carousel user interface element.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.

UI/UX Designer — ARTREZDEZ, NYC

New York City, NY | July 2021 - July 2021

- Redesigned Mobile iOS Application for Apple Store. Created deliverables on Figma and Adobe XD. Multiple iterations and variants of User Interface Elements.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.

UI/UX Designer — Sanchez Coffee CO.

Los Angeles, CA | November 2019 - December 2019

- Implemented Payment Gateway onto Payment Infrastructure with PayPal Manager, Stripe, Square. Designed and implemented Web Application Payment Platform with WordPress and Custom CSS/HTML. Designed Logo, Designed Packaging Design.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.

UI/UX Designer — California College of The Arts

San Francisco, CA | March 2019 - July 2019

- Designed Jekyll/Hyde HTML Markup Blog and maintained a web server with GitHub Pages.
- Collaborated with Graphic Designer to design a logo for a blog.
- Worked for Editor in Chief for creating the website and collaborated with team members.

Design Associate — Minted, LLC

Oakland, CA | October 2018 - December 2018

- Completed multiple roles in Print quality, design and quality assurance, met production quotas. Collaborated with customer service representatives to complete customer case tasks via Salesforce. Custom design work on various digital products, making edits to digital products, in Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop and Adobe InDesign.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.

UI/UX Designer — STEPSAVER

Huston, TX | November 2017 - December 2017

- Redesigned Mobile Application of SasS product from original mobile application designs. Designed Web Application UI Dashboard working closely with the lead developer to implement HTML/CSS/JS interface.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.

WEB DESIGNER — SONIC SYMPHONY

Los Angeles, CA | September 2017 - November 2017

- Received Legacy code, created flash HTML webpage and added extensive edits to original HTML.
- Design iteration till development, constant communication and transmission.

Web Designer — Alarm CCTV Distribution

Fremont, CA | June 2017 - August 2017

- Designed HTML Email Campaign template, utilized internal software application for email campaigns. Edited and
 maintained the company's collection of e-commerce websites. Made labels, Printed Labels, Packaging, Warehouse,
 Delivered Packages to Onsite rental offices.
- Created printed marketing materials for distribution, created packaging design of products, office tasks.

UI/UX Designer — ApexVR

San Leandro, CA | November 2017 - December 2017

• Designed VR Videography Web App that was developed by a Co-Developer built with Angular.JS, with VR functionality UI Web Component. Implemented VR video assets into Web App and created 2D design assets as deliverables.

Graphic/Web Designer — Tattoo Express Supply

Union City, CA | April 2017 to June 2017

- Designed print and digital marketing materials, designed flyers for distribution, maintained and made edits to WordPress E-commerce Platform with CSS/HTML.
- Web Design and Development for ecommerce WordPress website. On site application for digital assets. Branding, marketing additions for flyers, direct CSS, email templates, slider design as well as constant updates of product line.

Web Designer — POLAR-PRODUCTIONS

San Leandro, CA | January 2017 - February 2017

 San Francisco Bay Area videography production company, designed website with directions and developed on WordPRess CMS. Created and then hosted on AWS EC2 web servers, maintained good web practices, compression for assets and backups.

Graphic Designer — California Playgrounds

Fremont, CA | Nov 2016 to Mar 2017

- Design of supplementary marketing materials such as flyers and branded merchandise, digital assets for website.
- Assisted in converting over front-end design to PHP for self hosted WordPress Backend Development.

UI/Graphic Designer — 789tens

Honolulu, HI | November 2016 - December 2016

• E-commerce company located in Honolulu, designed with directions and developed website with DNN CMS. Created and then hosted on AWS EC2 Web Servers, additional graphic works for social media accounts,

UI/UX Designer — ArtistMichaelTodd

San Leandro, CA | June 2016 - December 2016

• Designed VR Videography Web App that was developed by a Co-Developer built with Angular.JS, with VR functionality UI Web Component. Implemented VR video assets into Web App and created 2D design assets as deliverables.

UI/Web Designer — iShopAway

San Leandro, CA | April 2016 - September 2016

• Contractor UI & UX Designer at iShopAway, an application startup in San Mateo, with direct supervision by the founder. Worked as a solo designer contractor under supervision by founder, research toward concept and marketing materials.

UI/Web Designer — Splice

Daly City, CA | Dec 2015 - Feb 2016

• Took careful care to follow founder's vision for an application that allows users to order pizza together with payment system. Designed mobile screens, with deliberate though on User Interface and User Experience, then created working prototypes.

Graphic & UI/UX Design Intern — Uguru, INC

San Francisco, CA | May 2015 - Nov 2015

- Completed internship at SF App Startup located at the Spear tower in SOMA. Designed High Fidelity UI design mockups in Adobe Illustrator for production applications. Prototyped rapid iterations of animations and transitions of mobile application screens.
- Designed User Interface and User Experience Designs for Clients across the United States and Canada. Maintained Websites and Web Servers, with HTML/CSS/JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, React.JS.